# **Tammy Batubo**

# Front-End Engineer



tammy.batubo@gmail.com



dev-tam.com



https://github.com/devTam

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Experienced Software Developer with a specialty in Front End development. Proficient in HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React as well as PHP and MySQL.Targeting a role as a Front End Developer to be a valuable asset in a great team.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **UI Engineer - contract**

Olla systems

Aug 2020 - Present

- Redesigned all pages of the solution in accordance to the style guide given
- Developed all pages including sign in, log in and password reset pages, vendors list and vendor pages.
- · Refactored the code bases and routing to follow the design flow

#### Front-End developer Intern

Google Africa Development Scholarship

May 2020 - Present

- Built a fully responsive Progressive Weather Web App and deployed to firebase
- Reviewed web apps built by other team members and improved overall performance and web accessibility stats.
- Collaborated with team members to test solutions before deploying to production.
- · Built an album store app with Angular

#### Front-End developer Intern

**HNG** Internship

May 2020 - Aug 2020

- Collaborated with Designers to build fully responsive websites and apps.
- Maintained an organized workflow using a project management tool (GitHub).
- Tested to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying.
- Documented bug reports, tickets, and any code changes.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Programming Languages**

JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS/Sass, PHP, GraphQL

#### **Libraries & Frameworks**

JQuery, React, Gatsby, Next.js, Bootstrap, GSAP

## **Tools & Platforms**

Git, Webpack, Netlify, Heroku, Firebase, Redux, react-redux, mySQL, VSCode, Apollo

## Design

Adobe Xd, Figma

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Zero To Mastery Academy**

The complete web development

# **University of Debrecen**

Medicine - MBBS